Guide to the David W. Dole ISCI Records, 1969-2004 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
David W. Dole ISCI records 1969-2004 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Dole, David W.
4 Linear Feet 1700 Items
David W. Dole is a genealogist and former broadcasting and advertising executive (Leo Burnett agency). The Industry Standard Commercial Identification (ISCI) system is a coding system used by television stations and advertisers to identify and track television commericials. The ISCI code consists of and 8-character identifier, four letters (identifying the advertiser) and four numbers (identifying the specific commercial), in the format ABCD1234. Each version of every commercial receives a unique identifier. David Dole is also the author (in the 1990s) of the Publishers Genealogical Coding Service (PGCS), used by librarians and genealogists to codify bibliographic information for obituaries.
The David W. Dole ISCI Records span the years between 1969 and 2004 and document the creation and management of the Industry Standard Commercial Indentification (ISCI) system. The collection consists of press releases, correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, articles, published registers, and technical documents that pertain to the proposal, design and implementation of the ISCI system. Materials pertain to the involvement of the Association of National Advertisers (ANA), the American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA), including the purchase of the ISCI system from Dole by the AAAA/ANA in the 1990s, and the replacement of ISCI with a new system, Ad-Id.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The David W. Dole ISCI Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008 and 2010.
Historical Note
The Industry Standard Commercial Identification (ISCI) system was created by David W. Dole, an executive in the advertising and broadcasting industries. ISCI was proposed to the American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA) and the Association of National Advertisers (ANA) in 1969 and adopted the following year as the standard method of providing unique identifiers for the handling, broadcasting, storage, and retrieval of television commercials. The system was maintained and updated by Dole until 1992, when it was sold to the two trade organizations. In 2007, ISCI was withdrawn from use by AAAA/ANA and replaced with a new system, Ad-Id.
Collection Overview
The David W. Dole ISCI Records span the years between 1969 and 2004 and document the creation and management of the Industry Standard Commercial Indentification (ISCI) system. The collection consists of press releases, correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, articles, published registers, and technical documents that pertain to the proposal, design and implementation of the ISCI system. Materials pertain to the involvement of the Association of National Advertisers (ANA), the American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA), including the purchase of the ISCI system from Dole by the AAAA/ANA in the 1990s, and the replacement of ISCI with a new system, Ad-Id.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three categories that largely reflect the condition of the collection upon arrival: Alphabetical Files; Chronological Files, and ISCI Registers. Alphabetical Files primarily include press releases, articles, clippings, and printed materials arranged alphabetically by originating source. Chronological Files primarily include correspondence, sometimes with clippings attached or interspersed, foldered by month. ISCI Registers include a partial run of published register volumes containing 4-letter alphabetical codes for all registered advertisers.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Dole, David W.
American Association of Advertising Agencies
Association of National Advertisers
Advertising research
Marketing research
Television advertising
Television advertising -- Automatic classification
Clippings
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
for related materials, see also the American Association of Advertising Agencies Records.
Contents of Collection
- Alphabetical Files, 1969-2003, (1 box)
  - A miscellaneous (Box 1)
    [Some items removed to Oversize Materials, Box 7]
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies)
  - Ad-Id
  - Advertising Age
  - ANA (Association of National Advertisers)
  - B miscellaneous
  - C miscellaneous
  - D miscellaneous
  - E miscellaneous
  - F miscellaneous
  - G miscellaneous
  - H miscellaneous
  - History of Dole's ISCI Ownership, 1969-1993
  - I miscellaneous
  - IAA (International Advertising Association)
  - International ISCI
  - ISCI
  - ISCI Registers
  - M miscellaneous
  - N miscellaneous
  - Q miscellaneous
  - R miscellaneous
  - S miscellaneous
  - T miscellaneous
  - TV Answer, Inc.
  - U miscellaneous
  - V miscellaneous
  - WFA (World Federation of Advertisers)
- Chronological Files, 1969-2005, (3 boxes)
  - 1969 July-1990 Dec., (73 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1991 Jan.-1992 Dec., (24 folders) (Box 3)
  - 1993 Jan.-2005 Aug., (52 folders) (Box 4)
- ISCI Registers, 1988-1998, (2 boxes)
  - 1988-1992 (Box 5)
  - 1994-1998 (Box 6)
- Oversize Materials, (1 box)
  - Alphabetical Files (Box 7)
    - A miscellaneous: American Map Company, map of the principal cities of the world, undated
    - Advertising Age articles, 1986-2002
    - M miscellaneous: Management Science Associates, PcMatching brochures, 1991